Siempre creí que las canciones podían llegar a cualquier parte en el viento.
La alegría y la tristeza, viajan más allá de las estrellas y llegan a todos en la Galaxia.
Si lo intento, volaré.
¡Si lo intento, volaré!
Yo me voy a unir...
...a las Walküre...
...¡Sea cómo sea!
Ha pasado más de medio siglo, desde que la humanidad migró hacia las estrellas.
A través de los años, se cruzaron con numerosas especies...
...y se estableció una civilización
interestelar unificada.
Sin embargo, aún existen muchas amenazas al acecho en el espacio exterior.
El síndrome VAR.
Repentinamente desestabiliza la mente de las personas y las empuja a un comportamiento violento.
La gente creció con miedo a que estos
trágicos eventos...
...podrían pasar en cualquier
lugar y momento.
Sin embargo, entre el miedo, algunos se levantaron para luchar.
La Unidad Táctica de Sonido, Walküre.
Ellas cantan con sus
voces trans-dimensionales...
...bajo la protección del Escuadrón Delta.
¡Inusualmente hermosa y adorable!
¡No existe puerta que no pueda abrir!
¡Soy la mecha-mecha más bonita con un cuerpo de ensueño!
¡Dejelo todo en mis manos!
¡La escurridiza Venus misteriosa!
¿Quieren saber más?
¡Para la batalla siempre OK!,
¡Yo soy la lider!
¡Encantada de conocerlos!
Para contener el creciente número de brotes del sindrome VAR...
...se convocó una rapida búsqueda de talentos para incorporar nuevos miembros.
¡Daremos lo mejor!
¡Sí!
Nosotras, las Walküre, arriesgamos nuestras vidas durante cada presentación.
¡Si no desean correr ese riesgo
pueden retirarse ahora!
Eso es todo.
¡Estoy muy nerviosa!
Ella dijo que vamos a arriesgar nuestras vidas...
¿Qué es eso?
Creo que van a grabar mientras
cantamos o algo así.
...¡Halo de guerra!
Cada vez más y más fuerte
Sus receptores Fold no están activados.
Más fuerte y cada vez más rápido...
Hmmm... no es bueno.
FALTA LINEA
La tercera fase de la audición
Walküre ha sido...
...insatisfactoria.
Todas fallaron.
TEAM FANSUB
Presenta:
Macross Delta
Walküre Apasionadas
¿La encontraste?
No.
Maldita polizón.
¿A dónde diablos habrá ido?
¡Qué dolor de cabeza!
De Enda De Enda Ulano
De glada rhyms klan delkez...
¿Qué?
Le de raam lom
FALTA LINEA
¡No!
Klano klano de aura
En la órbita alrededor del Planeta Ionideth
De fallo yoo zlam
FALTA LINEA
Tres degna zula
Del k...
FALTA LINEA
Un brote del sindrome VAR fue detectado en el planeta Ionideth.
¡Sujeta el equipo de clase 3!
Más del 70% de las fuerzas de la N.U.N.S. han sido afectadas.
¡Enciende ya!
Hemos detectado un
carguero civil en el sector.
Revisando sistema de eyección.
Escuadrones Alfa y Beta, protejan el Aether.
FALTA LINEA
Escuadrón Delta...
...asegurense que las canciones de las Walküres lleguen a Ionideth.
Unidad de Proyección, ¡Conectada!
M.M.P. Booster Pack, ¡Acoplado!
Todas las unidades del Escuadrón
Delta. ¡Catapultas listas!
Hayate, ¡Mirage!
Si arruinan todo otra vez, tendrán más que un recorte de salario.
Es hora que demuestren que no son más el "Duo Desastre".
¡Entendido!
¡Vamos pequeña señorita Jenius!
¡Tenemos a demostrarles de
qué estamos hechos!
Grandes palabras para un novato.
¡La música es amor!
¡La música es esperanza!
¡La música es vida!
¡Escuchen las canciones de las diosas!
¡Súper Dimensional Venus!
¡Walkure!
¡Las Walküre no se detendrán!
¡No!
¡Rockea mi jet!
Amor cósmico, ¡Despega!
Ah... enseñame ese rincon lejano
de mi infinita memoria
Donde las lágrimas derramadas
se volverán estrellas, ¿No?
FALTA LINEA
Ah...
Déjame escuchar el doloroso suspiro
de la canción de cuna
¡Que plasmaste en el
cielo de ese día!
FALTA LINEA
Si de repente mi cuerpo canta
Mi corazón empieza a bailar
Mi pecho se desborda...
FALTA LINEA
...¡De pasión!
¡Por eso no nos detendremos!
Abrazame así, hasta que
despierte del sueño
No necesito nada
Tampoco tu amor
FALTA LINEA
Porque me quiero romper, ¡Ah!
Así desnuda, mírame hasta
que amanezca
Desesperadamente
FALTA LINEA
Debes olvídalo
¡Todo!
¡No dejes de amar!
¡Las Walküre no se detendrán!
¡No!
Hmph, so he can read the wind a little.
¡Las Walküre no se detendrán!
¡No!
FALTA LINEA (Creo que dice Sorprendente...)
They're jumping between asteroids!
¡No!
¡Rockea mi jet!
Amor cósmico, ¡Despega!
FALTA LINEA (Hagamoslo)
Ah... contéstame, este es el límite de
la fiebre que me absorbe
Mi respiración alterada
se convertirá en viento
Ah...
Bromeando, en la noche oscura
flotó una luna de papel
FALTA LINEA (esa canción...)
Un cuento de hadas que a nadie contaré
Increible...
La canción de las Walküres detubo el VAR.
Es un misterio cuando el latido
de mi corazón resuena
Mi mirada se calienta
FALTA LINEA (They'll regret this...)
¡Vamos!, ¡Theo!, ¡Xao!
Estando juntos, cantemos....
FALTA LINEA
...¡Llorando!
¡Alpha!, ¡Caza Beta!, ¡Interceptenlos!
¡Por eso no nos detendremos!
Caza Alpha, ¡Entendido!
Atravieza el cielo así,
deteniendo mi respiración
Ahoguémonos en la noche
Cubiertos de mentiras
¡Quiero que me rompas!, ¡Ah!
Puedes acabar...
...conmigo, estoy preparada
Mis nervios
Y mi incomodidad
¡Son una herida!
...Fatal
¡Barrera Punta de Alfiler!
¿Huh?, El canto de las Walküres se detubo.
¿Están todas bien?
¡Teniente Messer!
¡Protegeré esta posición!
De Enda De Enda Ulano
De Glada Rhyms Klan Delkez...
Le De Raam Lom
Klano Klano De Aura
De Fallo Yoo Zlam
Tres Degna Zula
Del K Del K Zala
¿Ondas Bio-Fold?
No provienen de las Walkure.
¿Vienen de ese carguero?
De Aura De Molt'
Le ma Phor De Thola.
Aquí Delta 5.
Estoy detectando una onda Bio-Fold desconocida.
¡Voy a investigar!
¿Investigar?, ¡Delta 5!, no deje su posición!
Ah Mia Fallo Leez...
Proto Raam Leez...
Guirtezta!
Hel Te Gaam A...
Zala!
La música es...
Dejame subir gritando, ya no puedo detenerme
Silencioso amor que manda
una señal de S.O.S.
Halo de guerra
Mi historia había comenzado
cuando desperté
Algo se sentía diferente y me
froté los ojos con fuerza
Ya estoy lista para volar, 3, 2, 1...
FALTA LINEA
Desbordándolo todo
¡Mi motor a toda velocidad!
¡Detente!
Golpeada por una gota de Galaxia
Envuelta en ¡Deculture!
¡A toda potencia!, ¡Encenderé mi fuego!
Del sentimiento del vuelo,
ya no puedo regresar
¿Un canto?
Mi pecho se estremeció.
Esa voz...
Es alguien más que nosotras.
S.O.S. ardiente señal de amor
Yo...
¡El amor cambia el mundo!
Su canto... ¿Detuvo el VAR?
¿Estás herida?
¿Huh?
Rejájate, soy parte de Escuadrón Delta de Xaos.
Oficial del Complemento Hayate lmmelman (CREO QUE ESTA MAL EL RANGO)
Estoy aquí para mantener el VAR bajo control.
Escuadrón Delta...
¡Imposible!, ¿Están con las Walküre?
Sí, y ayudamos a rescatar a los civiles.
Pero pareciera que tu eres la única que rescataré aquí.
¿Huh?
Tu canto detuvo el VAR.
Se sintió muy bien.
Mi canto...
¿Estás bien?
¡Aguanta!
Es que estoy hambrienta.
Entonces, ¿Viajaste de polizón solo porque no quieres casarte?
¡Fue por mucho más que eso!
¡Tienen una audición para las Walkure en el planeta Ragna la próxima semana!
¿Huh?, esas audiciones ya finalizaron.
¿Eh?, ¿En serio?
Creo que ninguna logró entrar.
Todas las imagenes que obtuvimos de los desconocidos tienen interferencia.
Su combate aéreo y tecnología son de primera clase.
Excelente presentación hoy.
Bien, ¿Quieres un poco de medusa Barrette desmenuzada?
Voy a declinar su ofrecimiento.
Gracias por la ayuda de antes, Messer.
Sólo es mi deber.
¿Y qué hay de la candidata que encontró Hayate?
Es ella.
Su nombre es Freyja Wion.
Según el Oficial Hayate...
...iba en camino a la audición de las Walküre...
...cuando fue atacada por la tripulación del carguero infectada por el VAR.
Entonces, fue su canto el que suprimió al VAR.
¿Qué es esa cosa brillannte en su cabeza?
Una runa. Ella es Windermeriana.
¿Ella tiene Receptores Fold?
Sí.
Y sus lecturas son anormamente altas.
Y hablando de llegadas tarde...
¡Mmm!, no es mi culpa.
¡En mi barrio usan el antiguo sistema de calendario!
¡Es tan lindo!
¡Ahh!
¡Wow!, ¡Este es el cuartel general de las Walküre!
¡Hay tanto sonidos brillantes!
Te lo debo todo a tí, Hayate.
¿Huh?
Quiero decir, ¡Muchas gracias!
¡Por darme la oportunidad!
Bueno, te debia una por salvarme el trasero.
Además, aún no has logrado pasar la audición.
¡Diablos!, ¡Lo lograré de algún modo!
¡Es inmensa!, ¡Deculture!
Macross Elysion.
Es el cuartel general del Escuadrón Delta y el de las Walküre.
Ahh... ¡Hace que mi Runa brille salvajemente!
Entonces...  tu Runa es esa cosa que parece una antena.
¡Ah!, ¡Deja de mirarla fijo, pervertido!
¿Qué?, eso no significa nada para mi.
But are you actually serious? (NO SE SI DICE ESO)
Las Walküre ponen su vida en peligro y no es tan facil como parece.
Si lo intento, ¡Volareeé!
¡Yo quiero cantar las canciones que amo!
¡Por tanto tiempo como me sea posible hacerlo!
Por eso yo me voy a unir a las Walküre, ¡Sea cómo sea!
Tanto tiempo como ella pueda...
...Más fuertemente
Fuertemente y rapidamente
Más fuertemente
Entonces, ¿Esta es la nueva chica que Haya Haya descubrió?
No veo muchas lecturas.
Fuertemente y rapidamente
Quizás está nerviosa.
¿Dentro de su Runa?
Sí.
Hemos detectado pequeñas cantidades de cristales Bio-Fold.
Uno, dos, tres, cuatro.
Uno...
¡Freyja!
Lo... ¡Lo siento!
Solo debes concéntrate.
Cla... ¡Claro!
La música es
¡Misterio!
¡Vida!
La música es
¡Energía!
¡Esperanza!
¡No abandones!, el ejercicio físico es la base de nuestra fuerza
¡Sigan así!
La música es
¡Vida!
¡Energía!
La música es
¡Esperanza!
No serás aceptada...
...en las Walkure si eso
es todo lo que tienes.
La música es
¡Amor!
¡Misterio!
La música es
¡Vida!
¡Vitalidad!
¡Gori Gori!
La música es
¡Esperanza!
¡Amor!
La música es
¡Misterio!
¡Vida!
¡Gori Gori!
Si por ejemplo pudieras
ver el cielo terminar
Si temblorosa mi voz
pudieras escuchar
Volemos hasta que nos
lleguemos a desarmar
Con la canción rota de...
Receptores Fold no activos.
Ninguna onda Bio-Fold detectada.
Me pregunto por qué.
Los receptores Fold, generan ondas Bio-Fold
en sincronía con nuestra mente.
En el campo de batalla o cuando su vida está en riesgo, su reacción será más fuerte.
Ella quizás lo logre cuando subamos la apuesta.
Ella no puede ver sus pies.
No puedes volar... si solo miras al cielo.
¡Deculture!
Pero, ¿Esto está bien?, a esta hora de la noche...
No te preocupes, tengo permiso de vuelo.
A veces debes soltarlo todo y dejarlo salir, ¿Sabes?
Cierto, ¿No?
¡Soltemos todo y dejemoslo salir!
¡Vamos!
¡Hagámoslo!
Se siente tan irreal.
Volando con el viento así, solos tu y yo Hayate.
¡Oye!, cuando te ríes, tu risa en verdad es escalofriante.
¿Eh?, ¡Ciertamente no eres nada caballero!
¡Diablos!, es por eso que no eres popular entre las chicas.
¡Hey!, ¡Hey!
De todas formas... muchas "gazias".
¿Ah?, ¿Qué dijiste?
¡Ya lo dije!
¿En serio?, ¡Diablos!
Alguien anda esparciendo el rumor:
"El mundo algún día se acabará"
Eso es una mentira, por supuesto
Esa vez miré hacia el cielo
Ahora puedo sentir el futuro
¡Me sincronicé con tu estilo!
Izquierda, derecha, ¡Claro!
Encontré un buen lugar donde
una chica puede estar
Izquierda, derecha, ¡Claro!
Ese motor es...
Por eso debo hacerlo,
¡Ya no me puedo detener!
¡Ese idiota!
¡Prepárate!
¡Mi Runa brilla y resplandece!
¡Me estoy enamorando!
¡Es por tu culpa!
¡El brillo de mi Runa es invencible!
¡Se siente bien!
¡Ehhh!, ¡Uauuu!
¡Uuuu... Gori Gori... yyy!
¡Uaaa!
¡Oye!, ¡No puedo cantar así!
Lo siento, volar con tu canto se siente muy bien, ¿Sabes?
¿Qué?
Tu canto en verdad me revitaliza.
Hayate...
La música es energía.
Tienes razón.
Lynn Minmay.
Fire Bomber.
Sheryl Nome.
Ranka Lee.
Y finalmente, las Walküre, todos han dado mucha energía.
Yo quiero hacer lo mismo para la gente.
¿Messer?
Oficial Hayate Immelmann. (Subteniente Hayate Immelmann:) ERROR RANGOS!!!!
Este vuelo de entrenamiento con Freyja Wion no fue aprobado.
Regrese a la base de inmediato o será considerado insurrección, con lo cual deberé derribarlo.
¿De... derribarnos?
¡No seas tan obtuso!, yo solo...
¡Es verdad, nos acaba de fijar como blanco!
¿Qué está haciendo, Subteniente Mirage? (RANGOOSSSS)
¿Sabía de las acciones del Subteniente Hayate.... (RANGOOOOS)
...y esperabas detenerlo o cubrirlo antes que yo me diera cuenta?
Qué ingenua.
Lo siento mucho, Señor.
¿En serio?, ¡Yo debería ser a quien regañaran!
No es el punto.
Punto...
Pero, ¡Hayate lo hizo por mí!
Freyja Wion.
Esa actitud despreocupada tuya hará que te maten algún día.
¡Freyja y Mirage no tienen nada que ver con esto!
Cierto, es tu culpa.
El más pequeño error puede hacer que alguno muera.
No será tolerada ninguna insubordinación, con órdenes o sin ellas.
Fre Fre, ¡Llegas tarde!
¿Huh?, ¿Makina?, ¿Reina?
Fuiste a una sospechosa cita nocturna.
O quizás tuvo una cita amorosa amorosa (Parece que dice (love love dos veces, puede ser un detalle ponerlo asi)
Ci... ¿Cita?
Se equivocan, solo estaba entrenando para mañana.
Ella es aún más sospechosa cuando está inquieta.
No... no es...
Buenas noches, Freyja.
¿Kaname?
Esta noche tendremos una fiesta de bienvennida al estilo Walküre, Las chicas insistieron.
¿Al estilo Walküre?
La llamamos: ¡La fiesta de bienvenida en aguas termales bajo el cielo estrellado!
¿Huh? (MMMMMMM dudo que diga eso....)
En primer lugar, conozcamonos mejor entre nosotras.
Uno, dos.....
¡Ah!, la brisa nocturna se siente bien.
Fre Fre, te vas a marear si te quedas mucho tiempo bajo el agua.
Pe... pero, ¡Ah!
Pequeñas y púberes.
Dejame ver...
Hmm, tienes mejor figura que la de una citadina, pero necesitas tonificar más.
Blandas y escasas.
Cuando miro a Fre Fre, recuerdo el pasado cuando todas eramos nuevas en esto.
¿Eh?
Indecisas e improvisadas.
Ciertamente eso me trae muchos recuerdos.
Saben, solía ser una cantante solista en ese entonces.
Pero no lo pude aprovechar la oportunidad.
Tenía trabajos de una gran demanda física
en extraños eventos de degustación de comidas. (LARGAAAAAAAAA hay que decir lo mismos con otras palabras)
¿Hiciste esas  cosas Kaname?
¿Y luego de eso te uniste a Xaos? (NO ESCUCHO XAOS)
Fue entonces cuando Lady M conformó un equipo musical especializado.
¿Yo tengo receptores Fold?
Y la división cybernética del departamento de Inteligencia identificó a otra.
Una inteligente hacker que ha quebrantado la seguridad de numerosas organizaciones.
Acordó trabajar para nosotros en inteligencia, a cambio de borrar todos sus cargos.
¿Qué diablos habrá hecho?
Algo muy muy malo.
¿En serio?
¿Por qué aceptaste unirte, Kana Kana?
Como sea, pensé que al menos iba a cantar nuevamente.
¿Qué hay de tí, Makina?, ¿Por qué no declinaste la oferta?
Ellos te explicaron que no era una unidad de sonido comun.
Saben que en mi familia hemos tenido generaciones de mecánicos, ¿No?
Incluso, mi bis abuelo trabajó en el desarrollo de el VF-0.
Además, amo cantar y bailar.
Entonces, pensé que si me unía podría cumplir ambos sueños de una vez.
Realmente era tan ingenua.
¡Diablos!, ¿Qué es todo esto?
¡No te quedes allí!, ¡Muevete!
Al principio, ustedes dos, siempre estaba peleando.
Eso pasaba porque Rei Rei no mostraba ninguna motivación.
No estaba interesada en cantar.
Fue entonces cuando Lily Lily renunció.
Aún así, decidimos que las Walküre realizarían su debut.
Entramos en el campo de batalla dispuestas a lograrlo, pero...
Andrajosas y destrozadas.
Nuestra canto no llegó a nadie.
Las canciones de las Walküre no...
Para ser honesta, estuvimos pensando en renunciar.
¡Cha Ca Chan!, Unidad Táctica de Sonido, ¡Walküre!
¿Huh?
¿Qué es eso?
¡Usemos esto en el próximo show!
¡Usar ropa de combate en el escenario no animará a la audiencia!
¿Así que ese es el problema?
¡Sí, ese es!
Por cierto, ¡Hice para todas!
Toma.
Y toma.
Con el dedo extendido como si quisiera tocarte
Explotan mis ojos en cálidas lágrimas
...mis ojos en cálidas lágrimas
Ojos llorosos, Ah...
¿Por qué no podemos estar Juntos?
Donde haya un futuro
Veo una leve imagen residual...
...de ti en un rojo borroso
Mirando hacia el fuego brillante
Rechinan mis dientes como
una canción fúnebre
Nada está cambiando,
ni se resolverá
FALTA LINEA
¡Sí!, ¡No!
Tengo una pregunta en mi pecho
¿Todavía quedan fuerzas
para seguir adelante?
Ah, lo siento
Lo siento
Por poco respondo con
un "NO", pero...
Llora
Con el dedo extendido
como si quisiera tocarte
Como una tonta, sólo
puedo reaccionar así
Los latidos de mi corazón
me rompen toda y...
...explotan mis ojos
en cálidas lágrimas
¡Wow!, Fre Fre puede cantar con ojos llorosos (MMMM dicutir)
Teary-eyed, corazón palpitante. (mmmm dicutir)
¡Uh!... es....
Siento haberte interrumpido.
¡Esta bien!
Tu ya eres miembro de las Walküre.
¿Huh?, ah...
Muchas "gazias", por todo.
No tienes porque llorar.
Pero... no sabia que pasaron por todo eso.
Realmente, nada de lo que pasó fue planeado tras bastidores (revisar)
Incluso Clai-Clai que se esforzó tanto, no pudo soportarlo mas.
Entonces fue cuando...
...de la nada, Mikumo apareció.
Entonces esta nueva miembro...
...no vino a ninguna audición, ¿Cierto?
Contactos, influencias.
¿Acaso eres tú la nueva?
Cuando no pudiste alcanzar
Lo que viste en ese lugar
Pensaste en las cosas
que perderíamos
Yo, estaba profundamente conmovida.
Realmente me hizo pensar que era una diosa...
...y estaba entre nosotras.
Y también ocultaste tus lágrimas
Era un dolor hondo, fue la primera vez que una canción me llegó tan profundamente.
En esos ojos fijos
Que estuvieron perdidos
en este mundo
Yo me sentí devastada.
No dibujes tus sueños en soledad
Pero al mismo tiempo, no quería perder.
Me di cuenta de que un poco de competencia puede hacer que las Walküre sea un mejor equipo. (>LAAAAAARGAAAAA)
No verás el viento que
llegará hasta ti
Y lo hicimos, ¿No?
Somos lo mejor de lo mejor.
Freyja.
Tú también a partir de ahora.
Con tu espíritu volarás
más alto y más lejos
¡Sí!
¿Mikumo?
Toma mi mano y no la sueltes
¡Kumo Kumo!
Freyja.
¿Con qué sentimientos cantas?
¿Huh?, es que...
No respondas con palabras, enciende mi alma con tu canción.
Si no lo logras, Walküre no te necesitará más.
¡Bien!, ya es suficiente charla.
Entonces, ¿Listas para salir?
Por la Galaxia...
Por alguien allí afuera...
Ahora nosotras...
...Vamos a dar todo lo que tenemos.
...Mi corazón siente tu amor
¡Disfrutaremos hasta el final!
Adelante, ¡Walküre!
Bienvenidos al mundo Walküre
¡De verdad se siente bien!
Si lo intento, volaré... si lo intento, volaré... si lo intento...
¡Gori Gori!
¡La música es energía!
¡Es ella!
¡La nueva integrante!
¡Ella se cayó!
¡Miren eso!
¡Escuchen las canciones de las diosas!
¡Súper Dimensional Venus!
¡Walküre!
¡W... wa... walküre!
Presentemos a nuestra
nueva integrante.
So... soy de Windermere y me gustan las manzanas, soy Freyja Wion y tengo 14 años.
¡En... encantada de "conomerlos"!
¡Eres la mejor!
¡Encantado de conocerte!
Ahora, para empezar nuestra exitosa canción, "Change".
Si no puedes, estarás despedida.
Dazzled and shaken
It's a raging GIG revolution
My love for you,
Jealousy Mode -> Rescue
A butterfly sticks out its tongue,
a vortex opens, instant flood
Quickly now, before I fall into darkness
I'll melt you to a sweet glaze
Make a messy mismatch
Tearfully cheer you up
Set a burning fire
Gently bounce and fly away
Impatient, impatient
I want to tease, I want to be teased
Peek into my heart!
No, no, no, no
Dazzled and shaken
It's a raging GIG revolution
My love for you,
Jealousy Mode -> Rescue
(Head over heels, head over heels)
Fooled and tied down
Burning JAB love motion with you
Love, Fallen angel
impulse -> Hyperventilation
Sharp turn, sharp turn
Aroused and confused
It's a wild GIG evolution
You are love,
Soul Mode -> Get you
I realized
That it was useless to cry
Lost children
Escape the endless illusion
and are reborn
Somewhere in secret
Beyond the four seasons,
lies a fifth
Let's go look for it
A world of time and space,
Fly over it just like that
And you'll know fifth dimensional love
A todas las unidades.
¡Llego el momento!
Dazzled and shaken
Por el nuevo viento. (REVISAR)
It's a raging GIG revolution
Aether a Delta 1.
My love for you,
Jealousy Mode -> Rescue
Unidades desconocidas han entrado en órbita.
(Head over heels, head over heels)
Aquí vienen.
Aroused and confused
It's a wild GIG evolution
Malditas Walküre.
You are love,
Soul Mode -> Get you
FALTA LINEA
Get you
Se han esmerado en hacer su tarea (REVISAR)
De Enda De Enda Ulano...
Tengo que reiniciar el sistema de amplificación.
¿Que?
De glada rhyms klan delkez...
¿Qué es eso?
Mi señal no es consistente, ¿Puedes echar un vistazo?
Le de raam lom
Bien, en ese caso...
Klano klano de aura...
De fallo yoo zlam
Puedo escuchar una voz...
Tres degna zula
¿Alguien más está cantando, además de nosotras?
Del k del k Zala
¿La N.U.N Spacy nos ataca?
¿Es en serio?
¡Están afectados por el VAR!
Delta 3, ¡Verifica!
¡Sí, señor!
De auro de molt le ma...
¡Están en un 93.5%!
¡N.U.N Spacy y fuerzas Zentraedi afectados por el VAR!
Phor de thola
¿Incluso los Zentradi?
Ah mia fallo leez
Proto raam leez
¡Corran!
¡No es bueno, no es bueno! (REVISAR)
Guirtezta! Hel te gaam a...
No tenemos otra opción.
¡Inicien el ataque!
¡Protejan a los civiles y a las Walküre!
¡Entendido!
Zala!
¿No hay otra forma?
¿Disparamos contra aliados?
¡La musica podría regresar sus sentidos!
No hay tiempo para eso.
Este sector es muy poblado. (REVISAR)
Nuestro trabajo es proteger.
Incluso arriesgando nuestras vidas. (REVISAR)
Lo mismo aplica para los pilotos de la N.U.N Spacy.
¡Ellos sabían en qué se estaban metiendo!
¡Ahora, Messer!
Entendido. (REVISAR)
Este viento...
El es bueno.
¡Toma esto!
¡3, 2, 1!
¿Él los esquivó?
¡Cálmate!
¡Caballero Blanco!
Es rápido.
Hmm, este viento...
Es el de los asteroides.
Ese movimiento...
No puede ser...
¡Espera!
¡Cuidado!, ¡Rápido salta!
¡Gori Gori!
¡Cuidado! REVISAR
¡Mikumo!
¡Kumo Kumo!
Las Walküre están...
Así que lo han hecho. (REVISAR) Creo que ya es hora.
Al ver sus ojos me enamoré
En este éxtasis lo perseguiré
Pero quiero conocer aún más de él
y me quemo, me quemo por saber
Makina...
Rei Rei...
¡Nosotras también!
¡Sí!
Mientras más lo deseo, más misterioso se vuelve
Al desearlo más, mis
sentimientos se fortalecen
Por eso no voy a dudar en saltar
en este mundo desconocido
Será amor, será un sueño, aunque
todos crean en ellos
No ahora...
¡Es increíble!
No, estoy a punto de...
¡Ir contra algo de forma
apresurada es aburrido!
Ruru...
¡Ruru!
¡Ruru brillaaa!
¡Repentino amor!,
¡Frontera que no puedo cruzar!
¡Tiempo de mostrar un poco de
poder Windermere!
Sin importarme lo que sea
te mostraré cómo acabaré con todo
...Importarme lo que sea
¡Freyja!
¡Mente caótica!
se vuelve más complicada
¿Fre Fre?
Mi pecho siente su Runa.
Estas lecturas. ¡Ha despertado la canción de Freyja! REVISAR
Mi mente se está derritiendo,
pierdo el control de mi cuerpo
¡Estoy llegando!
¡Esto es una locura! REVISAR
¿Un Dios de la Muerte?
Los amigos con los que bromeé
Con los que deseé estar
en aquel tiempo
Por eso sé que un día me reuniré con ellos
y siempre estoy llena de vida
Cuanto más brillo, la sombra
más grande es
¿Estás bien Freyja? REVISAR
Cuanto más ardo, en más
cenizas me vuelvo
¡Hayate!
Cuanto más corro, más clara se vuelve
la peligrosa línea
Capitán, Hayate y Freyja...
¡Ah!, están bailando.
Yo nací pudiendo tener deseos
de libertad y la paz
Pero si me quedo quieta, me pudriré
¡Repentino amor!,
¡Peligroso sin fronteras!
Este ritmo...
Es irracional, lo sé
todavía puedo acelerar más rápido
Hayate es...
...¡Su color del viento!
Mente caótica
si hay un límite para mí
Estará bien si lo remarco
Pues destrucción y reconstrucción
es lo que puedo hacer
Deculture.
¡Buena suerte!
Qué me pasó...
Kaname...
¡Estamos volando! (Revisar)
¡Repentino amor!
¡Frontera que no puedo cruzar!
Sin importarme lo que sea
te mostraré cómo acabaré con todo
Mente caótica
se vuelve más complicada
¿Qué es... este sentimiento?
Mi mente se está derritiendo,
pierdo el control de mi cuerpo
Esta canción...
¡Estoy llegando!
¡El viento!
¡Repentino amor!,
¡Frontera que no puedo cruzar!
¡Misiles!, ¡Kana Kana!
Mientras siga ardiendo,
seguiré mostrando mi brillo
¡Teniente Messer!
¡Mente caótica!,
todo sea por ti
Maldición...
Gracias, Teniente Messer.
Todo sea por el futuro
cuantas veces tenga que destruirlo
¿Está bien?
¡Estoy bien!, Kaname, corre y reagrupate con los demás.
¡Sí!
Yo renaceré... por amor...
Para poder amar...
seguiré viviendo...
Freyja, receptores Fold activos.
Fre Fre vino cuando la necesitabamos.
El canto de Mikumo también se ha fortalecido
El canto de Freija... (REVISAR)
Estas son nuestras Walküre actuando para los tres desconocidos. (REVISAR)
That's our Walküre.
Now for those unknowns.
Hmph! Damn Walküre.
Malditas Walküre.
Esta farsa llega hasta aquí (REVISAR, NO CREO QUE DIGA ESO)
But this charade is over.
Nos tienen, Capitán Arad.
They got us, Major Arad!
¿Al Aether? (COMO ES LA NAVE)
What? The Aether?!
No, era una operación de distracción.
No, this skirmish. It was a diversion.
Mientras combatían contra ellos...
While you were occupied,
la Capital del planeta Voldor se rindió incondicionalmente al enemigo.
the capital of the planet Voldor
surrendered unconditionally to the enemy!
¿Al enemigo?, ¿Quiénes son ellos?
The enemy? Who exactly is...
Ese escudo de armas...
That coat of arms!
Lo sabía, son los Caballeros del Viento.
I thought so... The Aerial Knights.
Para la alianza de Brisingr
y toda la Galaxia:
To the Brisingr Globular Cluster
and the entire galaxy.
Soy el canciller del reino de Windermere, Roid Brehm.
I am the Chancellor of
the Kingdom of Windermere,
Raid Brehm.
No puede ser...
It can't be...
¿Windermere?
Isn't Windermere...
¡Freyja!
Freyja's...
Lord Roid...
Lord Rom'?
Hijos de la Protocultura ancestral.
To all children of the Protoculture.
Nosotros, el reino Windermere...
We, the Kingdom of Windermere,
...en nombre de nuestro Gran Viento y Rey Heinz Nerich Windermere...
in the name of the Great Wind,
and of His Majesty,
King Heinz Nerich of Windermere,
¡Windermere!
Windermere?
Al Nuevo Gobierno Unificado,
¡Le declaramos la guerra!
Hereby declare war against
the New U.N. Government!
What?
Hola Messer, ¿Cómo está tu herida?
Good morning, Messer.
How are you feeling?
Está bien.
I'm fine.
Pero tengo órdenes de someterme a un examen físico, para estar seguro.
But I have orders to undergo a
complete physical, just to be sure.
Messer, ya no se cuantas
veces nos salvaste.
Messer, you've saved us more times than...
Sólo cumplo con mi deber.
Just doing my duty.
Aun así, realmente te lo agradecemos.
Still... thank you. Really.
No es nada.
Don't mention it.
El reino de Windermere.
The Kingdom of Windermere.
El año pasado,su gobernante,
el Rey Gramia falleció
Last year their ruler, King Grammier,
said to be a wise leader, passed away,
y el Princie Heinz de 12 añosll
ascendió al trono.
and the 12-year-old Prince Heinz ll
ascended to the throne.
Al parecer esto también sacudió
su estructura política.
This also shook up
their political structure, apparently.
Freyja.
¿Si?
Yes?
¿Podría ser posible que
seas una espía de Windermere?
Could it be possible that
you're a Windermerian spy?
¿Una e...spía?
A s... spy?
¡Mikumo!
Mikumo!
Bueno,
de todos modos dudo que puedas hacer mucho como espía.
Well,
I doubt you'd make much of a spy anyways.
De acuerdo, escuchen.
Es hora de ponerse a trabajar.
Alright everyone, listen up.
It's time to get down to business.
Lady M sospecha que Windermere
Lady M suspects that Windermere
está detrás de la reciente avalancha de brotes VAR.
is behind the recent spate of Var outbreaks.
Windermere ha estado usando el VAR?
Windermere has been using the Var?
El síndrome VAR puede inhibir la autoconciencia
en aquellos a los que afecta..
Var Syndrome can inhibit self-awareness
in those it affects.
Preparandolos para ser controlados
remotamente por la mente de alguien.
Potentially priming them to be
remotely mind controlled.
Hasta ahora han sido...
So the Var outbreaks...
Experimentos.
Were experiments.
Probablemente.
Most likely.
Aunque en Voldor, la mayoría de las unidades de N.U.N
Spacy cayeron bajo su control,
Even on Voldor, it appears that most
of the N.U.N.S. forces were being controlled,
y el planeta se rindió sin oponer resistencia.
and surrendered without resistance.
¿Invadieron el planeta sin
ningún combate?
A whole planet taken without firing a shot?
¿Cómo hicieron eso?
How did they pull that off?
Escuché una canción.
I heard a song.
¿Una canción?
A song?
Esa era...la voz de un niño.
It was a boy's voice.
¿Un niño?
A boy...
Si, creo que tienes razón.
Yes, you might be right.
¿Un ángel o un demonio?
But was it the voice of an angel? Or a demon?
To be able to enslave so many
with the Var in but an instant.
That's quite impressive.
A song faster than light,
exceeding time and space...
Sounds kinda like the Singer of the Stars.
What's that?
It's an old legend.
A Windermerian one.
It's all about this
"bringing the light of life to runes" sorta stuff.
The Singer of the Stars...
Planet Windermere
Oh! The Knights have returned!
Reactivate the Protoculture ruins?
Yes. To maximize the effectiveness
of His Majesty's Wind Song.
As for Walküre,
during our last engagement
we identified a Windermerian defector
among them.
A traitor?
It's only a matter of time until
the Earthlings analyze her rune
and discover the connection between
certain songs and the Protoculture ruins.
Therefore,
we must reactivate all Protoculture ruins
within the Brisingr Cluster
and complete construction of the Fold
Wave Amplification and Transmission Field
before that happens.
We Windermerians
can feel Bio-Fold Waves with
our runes in the form of "Wind."
This is the evidence
that we are the rightful heirs
to the lost Protoculture.
Let us free the galaxy
from the grasp of the Earthlings
who continue to selfishly exploit it.
I don't care about the galaxy.
The skies of Windermere are enough for me.
That is so like you.
Being content with these skies...
Father, Mother, Mira, Anne, and Elle.
Please watch over me.
I shall avenge you, before my life burns out.
To the Fountain of Wind,
With the Wind...
Kassim, how old are you now?
I'm thirty-two.
My son is all grown up, so I can give my life
without any regrets.
The average lifespan of a Windermerian
is around thirty years.
My crystallization has developed this far.
But we will free the galaxy with our wings.
Until that day comes...
So Hayate, how's Freyja holding up?
She's taking it all pretty hard.
I can't blame her. I mean,
her home world just declared war on us...
So, how about we throw her a surprise party?
Huh?
November 3rd, the day after tomorrow is
Fre-Fre's birthday.
Her birthday...
Count me in!
Okay then, Rel-Rel and I
will handle the planning.
Leave the catering to me.
And everyone be sure to bring
a birthday present.
Then let's get this party started!
Yes!
Ah... um...
Yes.
Yeah, yeah. That's the spirit!
A present, huh...
Hmm... no, this just isn't her.
I'm stumped. I wonder what sorta
stuff she likes...
Surely you know Freyja better than I do...
You think so?
Things that she likes...
Can't think of anything
except singing and apples...
Do you happen to like Freyja?
Huh? She's just a...
friend... nah.
We're not really partners in anything...
Teammates?
It's like...
I never get tired of watching her.
She's never boring.
I see.
But those sorts of feelings can often
lead to something more, right?
Say, how about this?
Grab that.
- Okay!
- How are we on drinks?
Give me a hand here!
Decorations?
All good!
Same here.
Preparations complete.
Food?
Okay---...
Messer! Should you be on your feet?
Yes. Commander Arad said he
wanted all hands on deck tonight.
The Commander did?
- Really?
- Well, yeah...
And the cake?
Nearly done!
By the way, where the heck is Hayate?
He isn't still looking for a present, is he?
It's pitch black...
I'm home.
Uh... where is everyone?
Wha, whaaa... What's goin' on?!
A one-two!
Happy Birthday!
Huh? Birthday...
Ah... whoa!
Today's my birthday!
You forgot?
Well, during the last couple years,
whenever it was my birthday,
the mayor was always telling me to
"hurry up and get married,"
so I was always busy
trying to stay out of his way.
- Seriously?
- That must have been pretty rough.
Hayate?
Damn it!
These are from all of us!
Wow... this many?
Is this really okay?
Mikumo...
Kumo-Kumo?
Super rare.
Glad you could make it, Mikumo.
Happy Birthday, Happy Birthday
Happy Birthday to you
Wishing the best dear Freyja
Happy Birthday, Happy Birthday
Happy Birthday to you
Happy Birthday to you!
Freyja.
Blow out your candles.
Congratulations!
Thank you... thank you!
Thank you, everyone!
Now, a few words from Fre-Fre!
Sure!
Damn, I'd better move it.
Well...
When I was little, people from Earth
lived near my village.
They taught me songs from Earth,
and we sang together at local festivals.
I thought those songs were amazing.
They could even bring people
from different planets together.
I was really moved.
But then, seven years ago, the war happened.
All the people from Earth disappeared.
Even my parents joined the Wind.
But no matter how tough things got,
I always had my songs.
So when I heard how Walküre
saved people by singing...
I knew I just had to join...
Where have you been?
You'll see.
Today, I turn fifteen.
For a Windermerian,
this marks the midpoint of one's life.
To be able to spend this important day...
as a member of Walküre...
Fre-Fre!
I'm so happy to have met all of you!
I'm gonna bring the energy
and keep on singin'!
Fre-Fre!
We're a team forever!
There, there.
Alright, let's get this party started!
Look, look!
Guys, look at this!
What's going on?
Snow...
It's snow... Snow-PIKA!
Hey!
He did this for Freyja?
Awesome!
Whoa, I've never seen snow before!
Wow, Deculture!
Haha... Oh geez.
Happy birthday, Freyja!
Oh, Hayate.
Sorry I was late, Freyja.
So you're the one that made it snow like this?
Pretty much.
Think of it as a birthday present.
Thank you, Hayate!
Do you like it?
Yeah. It's totally Gori-Gori!
Your rune's all glowy.
I close my eyes and make a wish
Don't say it, but I believe it!
I can always feel
The up & down of your heart
I won't forget this moment
as we gaze into each other's eyes
This feeling, about to overflow (feeling)
Always makes me wanna
burst into tears (always)
Don't let go of this fading
fragment of destiny
God Bless You
We met within a shining wind
No more hesitating
Hearts on fire, right now
God Bless You
Did you somehow realize all this from the start?
Thank you for watching over me
Thank you for staying
BY my side
if into your heart
fell a single grain of (pale sorrow)
Since I have no memory of anyone
ever celebrating my birthday.
Just shine a ray of light
(to chase I! away)
It's not just my birthday. I have no memory
of my parents or where I grew up either.
If this is a miracle, please God,
guide all of this love
God Bless You
Freyja.
What is it that you wanted to talk about?
It's so pretty.
Kaname.
What is it?
AXIA. This song...
This song saved me.
Two years ago, I nearly succumbed to the Var.
What?
It was your singing that held me together.
Since then, your singing has
meant everything to me.
But I'm not able to protect you any longer.
I'm truly sorry.
Messer...
Messer's been taken off active flight duty?
The results from his physical came through.
Due to repeated bouts of Var, he's suffering
from multiple organ dysfunction.
His body has reached its limit.
Limit?
I'll inform the others tomorrow.
You already knew, didn't you?
He said he wanted to protect
Walküre, no matter the cost.
So Arad and I got permission from Lady M.
I think you all went too far.
I think so too.
The Knights' notorious initiation ritual
can be a little rough.
I went through it as well.
Although I think you're the first person
to give as good as he got.
I would've won if it was a fair fight.
I can't stand those who act big
just because they're older!
Same here.
I'm Raid Brehm.
Nice to meet you.
Keith Aero Windermere.
One day, let's...
stir up a great wind in this galaxy.
Roid...
Where are you flying now?
During our last engagement,
strong Bio-Fold Wave readings were detected
from the Protoculture ruins on Al Shahal.
It's possible that Windermere
is using the power of the ruins
to amplify the transmission
of its mind control song.
This requires a more hands-on approach.
After landing on Al Shahal,
we'll activate the ruins with Walküre's
singing and collect any readings.
But how? Al Shahal is under
Windermerian occupation.
Yeah. We can't just walk in the front door.
But we have a plan!
Welcome to Walküre World
Huh? What's that?
Look at that, look!
Welcome to Walküre World
To everyone watching the Galaxy Network.
With the Globular Cluster currently
under Windermerian control,
Welcome!
to hold anti-Vár vaccine concerts in person.
My Heart... feel your love
So we've decided to hold a special concert
Welcome to Walküre World
Surpassing nations, planets, even the galaxy,
we wanna send good will out to all!
We hereby declare that we will not yield to
Windermerian subjugation!
May the songs of goddesses
sound throughout the galaxy!
Frenzied screaming!
There's no stopping now!
"S O S" Sirens ring out
Love! Halation THE WAR
When I wake up,
the story begins (My own story)
The broadcast data carries one of
Reina's special automated viruses.
There's something different this morning
I rub the sleep from my eyes
It spreads via various communication devices
Fully loaded,
connected to the Galaxy Network
throughout the Globular Cluster.
My engine is revving, full speed ahead!
Multiplying exponentially and eating its way in.
Collision on a galactic scale
CRASH! A rush of Deculture!
Hard to starboard! I'm firing up
Meaning that the enemy won't be able
to see anything other than Walküre!
Feel it diving!
There's no turning back now!
As they say, "the best place to hide a jellyfish
is among other jellyfish."
"S O S" The signal burns
Love! Changing THE WORLD We've even prepared a
little something to hold people's attention.
Let's click!
Thanks for your support!
Here's a little something from Maki-Maki.
Colors so bright and radiant
Deculture!
While carrying out the infiltration,
- Thanks for your support!
we can also make some money
by selling video footage.
You're quite the businessman.
I'm the kind of girl that flies out into space
to accept a challenge
Walküre!
There are so many sounds
You don't know in this world
Melodies you don't know
Lights out
Start up
A foolish dancer who hides
A useless, crazy love
Which cannot be cried enough about
(Sing with 5 prayers now)
I... it's not what you think!
Hear the Universe!
Studying what?!
You are the crazy one living
This is enemy propaganda! Idiots...
Within a story that no one will tell
How do you turn this thing off?
Just go ahead and provoke me
Garbage. Trash.
Risk your life in the night!
Do as your heart desires, come on
I am an unconquerable woman.
You'll get nowhere with me for so little.
Just go ahead and challenge me
Hold me shockingly tight
Damn you, Walküre!
Hurry up, while there's still time
Wide-scale communications failure confirmed.
We're in.
All units, activate stealth mode and
commence operation!
- Roger!
- Oorah, sir!
I'm standing on top of burning rubble
I forget why and from when
What... is this feeling?
But within these suffocating flames
Damn, what is this?!
It's meaningless to keep on searching
Destroy, overcome, the ecstasy of the past
Reaper... where are you?
Even if it's the worst, choose the future
Here we go
Love forever until it's almost too much
If we sing until it hurts
Our souls get wound up, yeah
Bu! if we continue to scream
What is this sound?
But if we continue to scream
They're trying to capture the ruins...
Now to counter them with the Wind Song.
What lies beyond is the destruction of innocence!
De Enda De Enda Ulano
Running with a whirlwind of insanity in my heart!
De glada rhyms klan delkez...
For how far and how long, I know not
Le de raam lom
What's this interference?
Klano, Klano de aura...
- Whaz' is this?
- Could it be...
De fallo yoo zlam
Captain, gigantic structures have appeared
on all planets with Protoculture ruins.
Tres degna zula
Gigantic structures?
Del k, Del k Zala
If we dance until we go crazy
De Auro De Molt
Le ma Phor De Thola...
But if we continue to move
If we can reach the sky so bright
What lies beyond is the destruction of innocence!
Innocence!
Innocencel!
Innocence!!!
Innocence!!!!
Innocence!!!!!
- Mikumo!
- Fre-Fre!
This wind?
The Singer of the Stars...
The enemy's song has ceased.
We must protect the
Protoculture structure.
Take them out now!
Da!
We're surrounded!
They've caught us in a pincer attack!
Damn... without Messer...
Kumo-Kumo, snap out of it!
Kumo-Kumo!
Freyja! What happened to your hand?
Freyja, is that... crystallization?
Crystallization...
Freyja's life is in danger!
Delta 5! Check your 5:00.
Son of a-! The White Knight?
Got you now!
Now is our chance to crush Walküre!
"Da!
"Roger!
Freyja!
I can't shake him!
I thought you'd at least be able
to ride the wind a little...
He's here!
What the...
Heh.
That's...!
What?
Delta 2, engaging!
Messer, are you out of your mind?!
I got word of the situation.
What are you trying to do?!
lam still...
a member of Delta Flight!
Messer!
Hehe, you're finished.
What the...?!
Kaname, are you okay?!
Lieutenant!
Sing for me, Kaname!
Messer!
Sing for me...
before I turn completely!
Kaname!
All right, Messer!
Thank you, Kaname.
That smile I just saw
Might be the last I ever see
Even a glimpse of your profile
When talking to someone else
Is precious to me
In this world where feathers become heavier than life
You give me a reason to live - This guy!
-How is an outsider able to--- ?
You give me a reason to live
That's why we met
Longing is the AXIA in my heart!
Soaring with the flush of this unrequited feeling
You, so distant
Like a cruel rainbow
Vanishing all too soon
I love you but hate you
He's... turned Var.
But he's still in control?
How beautiful...
Born alone
Everyone dies alone
But despite this
We cannot just live alone
Transmitting these waves of longing
Love soaking into this aching wound
The one word I couldn't say
Floods my vision
Even through tears, AXIA brightens the future
Its pulse connected by faint particles
Like a dream floating in a haze
A heartless passion, faking eternity
White Knight!
Messer!
Are you okay, Messer!
Messer.
No...
Thank you... Kaname.
Don't talk.
I could hear it, your song, "AXIA."
Huh?
Ever since I heard you sing, I've...
Messer?
Messer!
This is bad.
Look out!
Did I get him?
Hayate!
Makina, hold on!
- Makina!
- Makina
Walküre's been captured by the enemy.
Warrant Officer Hayate immelmann and
Second Lieutenant Mirage Farina Jenius
are both missing in action.
First Lieutenant Messer lhlefeld
has been killed in action.
We don't have time to feel sorry
for ourselves, Lieutenant.
Yeah, we have to see this through to the end.
For his sake as well... for Messer.
Yes, sir.
So what's the situation with the ruins?
They've appeared on seven
new planets, including Ragna.
An investigation is underway.
Captain, Windermere is
broadcasting a transmission
galaxy-wide.
The Protoculture ruins have awakened
in response to His Majesty's Wind Song.
This is undeniable proof that we are
the chosen ones.
And now, they too have agreed to
fight by our side,
to join our stand against the tyranny
of the New U.N. Government.
They?
Our new allies, Walküre.
Behold, the combined power of goddesses
and the Wind Song!
Gather to the side of Walküre
and His Majesty Heinz,
Children of the Protoculture!
That's some impressive propaganda.
Mirage.
Hayate...
Makina...
Pull it together, you two.
No matter what happens,
never forget we're Walküre.
Kaname.
Yes.
On your feet. Supreme Commander Roid
wants to see you.
The Supreme Commander?
Welcome, Walküre.
Goddesses of the battlefield.
Where are Mikumo and Makina?
Makina Nakajima is being treated
in our infirmary.
She should make a full recovery.
Makina.
Our science team has
analyzed Mikumo Guynemer.
Analyzed?
As I had suspected, she is no mere human.
She is, in fact, a specialized clone.
That can't be.
The Galactic Treaty prohibits
the practice of genetic cloning.
It would hardly be the first time
Earthlings have broken it.
That's...
It appears they really didn't tell you anything.
Like the fact that Mikumo's genetic material
was made from the cells of
the Singer of the Stars,
which New U.N. Spacy
stole from us seven years ago.
The Singer of the Stars?
Isn't that just a legend?
I believe that N.U.N.S. handed the cells over
to Xaos' Lady M.
Resulting in the creation of the musical
weapon known as Mikumo Guynemer.
Musical weapon?
Music is not a weapon!
Don't you realize that your
singing could be an experiment
to utilize Bio-Fold Waves
for military purposes?
Such is the way of Earthlings.
Not all Earth people are bad!
They were the ones who started
the war seven years ago!
That may be so, but...
Do you believe they are worth
risking your life to protect?
We won't forgive Walküre!
Traitors!
I knew it! Freyja Wion was a spy all along!
No...
What is this?
Why are they saying we're traitors?
The minute you went missing,
this is how they reacted.
So, why don't you give up
singing for such people
and sing for us instead?
Roid, what are you doing?
If His Majesty Heinz and Walküre
were to combine their talents...
their songs would be able to reach
not just the Globular Cluster,
but the entire galaxy as well.
And if we utilized the information
contained in Mikumo's genes...
Freyja Wion, we might be
able to halt your crystallization,
possibly even reverse it.
Freyja's...
I shall ask you once more.
Do you really intend to continue
singing-risking your lives-for them?
Even if it's for the sake
of only one person,
- Walküre will...
-keep on singing.
Even if my rune's wind fades!
Is that so...
Confine them to solitary.
Yes, sir!
I felt your song in my rune.
The Reaper.
It was a noble wind,
befitting of him.
We are about to commence a surprise assault.
N.U.N.S. will sit this operation out.
This is because our prolonged
exposure to Walküre's music
is thought to have increased
our resistance to mind control.
Let's show 'em the true meaning
of Yack Deculture!
Macross Elysion,
full speed ahead!
I had His Majesty Heinz return to Windermere.
His Bio-Fold Wave readings
were extraordinary.
But I'm afraid they do not
compare to Mikumo Guynemer's.
And if we continue to study Walkfire...
our findings may help to cure
His Majesty's condition too.
I care not about any "readings."
Have you ever stopped to
feel His Majesty's singing?
Everything I do is for our ultimate
victory. We cannot afford to lose.
Lord Roid, we have detected a Fold signature.
A large enemy fleet is
headed towards us.
Understood.
They're here.
Hayate...
We managed to sneak aboard somehow...
But it looks like Walkfire
is on a different ship.
Freyja...
Walküre's been captured,
Lieutenant Messer was...
And on top of that, even Freyja is...
I don't wanna hear you whining.
I wasn't whining!
We have to...
We have to do this,
for Messer's sake, too!
You're right.
It's times like this when your
simple-mindedness actually helps.
Is that supposed to be a compliment?
Half a compliment.
Anyway, we have to find a way out of here.
Yeah.
We will break through the asteroid belt
straight towards the enemy's main fleet.
The Macross Grasion will position
itself to upper starboard,
and the Megasion to the lower port side.
Once we reach the enemy,
fire your main cannons immediately,
and break through the Sigur Berrentz's barrier!
Macross Grasion, ready when you are.
Hmph, time to show them what we've got.
Megasion, roger that.
Let's put the wind up these windy chaps.
To all assault teams:
Rescue Walküre
and make the galaxy safe again!
- Roger!
- Oorah, sir!
The new Armored Unit will take point!
Strap yourselves in, boys!
Let's show them who has the big guns!
Enemy fleet within range!
Multiple bandits on approach!
All forces, commence Operation Ragnarok!
What?
What's going on?
The battle's started?
That's Messer's Valkyrie...
They must have brought it on-board
to study its combat capability...
What's going on?
Heh, now that's what I call galactic standard.
I'll take a Draken 111 and change
its transponder code.
This is...
What's wrong?
That's from your welcome party,
and that must be his old squadron.
I heard that they were wiped out
two years ago while fighting the Var.
That Reaper, he's... he's smiling.
I think that maybe Lieutenant Messer
was trying to fight
for the sake of his teammates.
Just like how he tried to protect Kaname...
He was surely watching out for us as well.
That's why he was able to be so strong.
Even if it meant sacrificing
or isolating himself...
it was worth it if he had something to protect.
What the hell? You were far more
than just the Reaper, weren't you?
You didn't have to play the tough guy.
This is your stage, Singer of the Stars.
Bring a new wind to the galaxy with your song.
This is not Walküre's stage.
Walküre's fate is also in your hands.
I had hoped not to resort to this, but...
A certain phrase was passed down to
the Royal Family along with your legend.
Rudanjaar Rom Mayan.
Rudanjaar Rom Mayan!
Ruks sentiele
The Wind Song... No, this is different.
Cartim Iiehs Iema
Lu Arma la nia mikra
Te zveram/ vinikatch
Macross Megasion, destroyed!
Ahmia gan thirschmek
Has Walküre betrayed us?
Enohrma Iaeb Ohro oblik
They're being mind controlled.
Mi arkhamao Toh yoohenbor
Aula nobre diohs
Mikumo? But why?
It hurts... it hurts, Mikumo.
It stings, it stings... such sadness.
Mikumo, what's happening? Mikumo!
Do you remember
Ulano plache te auro melrakez kum
Vam likormemora ekno
Laam zertza alkhamao fleah flan
We must rescue Mikumo and Walküre!
Oorah, sir!
Where are we?
Why are we on Ragna?
White Knight, the Sigur Berrentzs!
Roid, what are you up to?
The time has come.
For all the winds of the galaxy to be as one!
Do you remember
Ulano plache te auro melrakez kum
Vam likormemora ekno
Laam zertza alkhamao fleah flan
Roid, what is this?
The Star Song will activate
the Protoculture System.
Mi arkhamao rhymsklan
Our winds will be as one?
Achra degnor zed
no, we will become the very galaxy itself!
Wira gan Lu Ramuhr
that the Protoculture envisioned!
Brakuz natierka
Zertza cafierma kverneh
That means...
the entire galaxy will be
under their mind control...
We must stop the Star Song at all costs!
I'm not alone anymore,
Now that you're here with me
Klano, Geu, Imnidadt!
Omuni enorme tle vinikatch zvard
Nadthi zidous ezqezigk per phodlodz mi zohn
Apridie kchu zertza inos umdesheo
Now, you and I are the galaxy itself.
Planat eterno vaight
Let your song ring throughout us
A mia inos Auro
Hayate...
Freyja.
Hayate.
When my Rune shines bright
Wow woh wow woh
I'm gonna fall in love
Hayate!
I'm still alive.
I can still sing.
If I love only once,
let's play as one inside your soul
Let's share a selfish kiss!
She's risking her life to sing.
This flower, its petals are falling
The night sky, its stars are countless
I swallow my tears, blaming you for it all
But I can't reveal this feeling to anyone
(Reach) Until it breaks
(Reach) Until it takes flight
Let's rescue Mikumo and Makina!
(Until the end) The secret prayers
(Of time) Hidden in my heart!
Keep feeling, keep believing
Send it all flying
GYUN! GYUN! GYUN!
If I love only once, let's play as one inside your soul
Let's kiss faster than light, just wait for me!
This body I've almost forgotten
Ugh... stow.!
This heart that's all I can hear
Break free from the shackles of your dreams
Come on, take me away, come closer, don't stop
De... culture
Rei-Rei, Fre-Fre, Kana-Kana.
When lightning scorches the night sky
It also sets my passions aflame
I'm reminded that the mind and body are one
Words can't express this restlessness
(The two of us) Encountered each other
(The two of us) Searched for one another
(Shining) The fire of your life
(In the dark) Bloomed in the sky
Keep bursting, keep sparkling
Messer?
Shoot through my heart
BANG! BANG! BANG!
Let's dance in your dreams,
with passion never to be felt again
With your arms as wide as the sky,
hold me tight
We need a strength that will endure,
a bond that will last
We will live through time together,
so you'd better be ready
Go on, take me, bind me, don't stop
- Mikumo.
- Mikumo!
- Kumo-Kumo.
- Mikumo.
Mikumo!
You're not alone.
You're not alone, Mikumo!
You're one of us!
Don't ignore your desire
Come and catch me
Ah... their song gives me strength.
Faster than you've caught anything before
If I love only once, let's play as one inside your soul
Let's kiss faster than light, just wait for me!
- She's back.
- Kumo-Kumo.
This body I've almost forgotten
This heart that's all I can hear
Break free from the shackles of your dreams
Delta 5, lead the enemy away from Walküre!
Come on, take me away, come closer
Let's dance in your dreams, with passion
never to be felt again I'm working on it!
Let's dance in your dreams,
with passion never to be felt again
With your arms as wide as the sky,
hold me tight
We need a strength that will endure,
a bond that will last
We will live through time together,
so you'd better be ready
Go on, take me, bind me, don't stop
- Mirage!
- I'm not done ye“!
This transponder code!
No doubt about it. It's Mirage and Hayate!
What? They're alive?!
Mikumo's Fold Receptors
are going off the charts.
Ours, too...
Did Lady M create Kumo-Kumo
to control the Protoculture System?
And gathered us so she'd have
someone she could connect with...
No.
The reason is unimportant. Music is neither
a weapon nor a tool of war.
Kumo-Kumo!
I love singing.
The music flows out from within me.
Yep! Singing has gotta be...
who I am!
Within the overflowing darkness
Another spark of light gathers
Hayate, Mirage, Chuck.
At the end of its long journey
It embraces the tired voice
When miracles happen,
a closely intertwined melody springs to mind
Strong enough to blow awe y even black gra vity I'll fight to protect
what's important to me! There's more to me than just my grandparents!
Strong enough to blow away
even black gravity
I can hear you Freyja.
The song you're risking your life to sing.
This borrowed sky
changes to infinity with us five
That' answer should be enough-
Now hurry To protect your song!
That answer should be enough.
Now hurry
"Why don't you look up?"
If even one of us is missing,
then it's all meaningless
Why don't you understand?
The entire galaxy is about to be connected
We reconfirm our bonds, again and again.
and people will be able to live forever!
What's this dark and disturbed wind?
Roid!
What's going on?
Th-this is...
A deep sorrow...
Loneliness? Despair?
- Throbbing and stabbing.
- Hurting itself.
Hayate! He's...?
Gotta send him... send him my song!
If I try...
I can... fly!
Freyja's Rune-Pika!
Freyja!
Until the day our voices are silenced, we'll sing
Freyja.
She jumped to take her song to him.
We're jumping too!
Yeah!
Hayate!
Those glances and words we shared
Even the memory of
our paths crossing makes me happy
Everyone!
Pulses quickening, where to next?
Hold on so we're never separated
Everlasting (voices) (echo) in the distance
We cried (We called),
We were screaming
(Always) missing you, your courage
Walküre's song, it's...
If the blue sky, the clear wind,
Even the stars betray you
Only we will never betray you,
we won't betray you
Overcoming separation and sadness
The dream quintet continues on
Beyond hesitation, looking to tomorrow,
chasing it - The Macross! - This is bad!
Beyond hesitation, looking to
tomorrow, chasing it
Until the day our voices are silenced, we'll sing
Too slow!
Even when the noise threatened to swallow us
I could always feel this brilliant warmth
Walküre's Bio-Fold Waves
are increasing rapidly!
Because this unforgettable melody
will surely reach
Your wounded heart, those strong eyes
(Words) we can't say (echo) afar
We flew (We called),
What were we doing?
Your (smile), gently (floating)
It's tantalizing, somehow
Run, love. Run further still
Those warriors and
the five colors of their winds.
With hands held
They're risking their lives, the same as Heinz.
The thrill will never betray you,
it won't betray you
We all live by our own winds.
Making them all into one is...
More than a solo, more than a due!
We're matching our winds with Walküre's!
The quintet of longing prayers
Huh? Da! Uh...
Will pull you in and embrace you,
just as when we first met!
Until the day our voices are silenced, we'll sing
Aerial Knights to Xaos:
We will provide support for Walküre.
Support?!
I sense a strong disturbance in the wind
at the center of the great temple.
We shall approach using Walküre's
singing to calm the disturbance,
striking together and freeing
the wind once more!
Da!
- This is awesome!
- Working together...
If we destroy that thing we can save Freyja.
Why?
Why don't you understand?!
May this song somehow reach
Ugh... they're fast!
The distant future, yet to take form
If the blue sky, the clear wind,
Even the stars betray you
Only we will never betray you,
we won't betray you
Now forge ahead, wipe away your tears
The strong, everlasting quintet
Leave this to us!
Will chase tomorrow to eternity and embrace it
Until the day our voices (these voices)
are silenced, we'll sing
Those two have the same wings that you did,
Messer.
Let's end this, Mirage!
Take this!
If even one of us is missing,
then it's all meaningless
We reconfirm our bonds, again and again
And just believe
If you're going to fall apart,
do it after this is all over
Let the wind be free, Roid!
We will deliver cheerfully blossoming bouquets
Leave him to me.
Images of sound beginning to dance
Smiling faintly
Let the song of joy ring out
Far into the distance
Now!
Until the day our fate changes
Roid, why would you do this?
Eternity...
Eternity will
free the wind of Windermere
from the shackles of its fleeting existence,
and bring eternal peace to our skies.
What have you done...
I already felt eternity once, long ago.
Roid, it was when I flew with you
in that sky that day!
With me?
Of course, on that day... eternity...
it was right there...
White Knight!
Roid, my brother Keith...
I shall create a new wind
throughout the galaxy for both of you!
Commander Arad.
It appears that Windermere wants
to enter into peace negotiations.
Do you think the U.N. Government
will accept their offer?
New U.N. Spacy is already at its limit.
And then there's the fact that they
stole the cells of the Singer of the Stars.
Lady M made sure to keep
very thorough records.
Hayate!
Freyja!
Kaname, Reina, Makina, Freyja!
- Mikumo!
- Kumo-Kumo
- Freyja!
- I'm so glad you're all safe!
Girls... here I come!
Jellyfish send-off?
Here on Ragna, there's an old belief that
the spirits of the dead
return to the sea and become Light Jellyfish.
By drifting slowly through the ocean
they are healed, little by little,
until they become beautiful and are reborn.
Until they become beautiful...
That's why we send off the spirit in a boat
so it can become a beautiful jellyfish.
I could never keep up
You were always
Looking out at something from this place
Counting those things that, once possessed, are lost
You were hiding your tears, weren't you?
Whether they're friends or foes,
if a battle has casualties...
That intense gaze of yours
- I'd like to win someday.
- Yeah.
Saw the world in a different light
Dreams aren't reached alone
They fly to us on invisible winds
So if you feel you can soar high and far
Your singing granted life
to this artificial body of mine.
Please don't let go of this hand
There are those that treasure my... our music.
That's why I... why Walküre sings.
The Song of Life.
Dreams aren't reached alone
They fly to us on invisible winds
So if you feel you can soar high and far
Please don't let go of this hand
I know your blues...
Welcome, welcome, welcome
Welcome to Walküre World
Wow wow wow wow woo!
Dancing in the Moonlight
You only live once
Never wanna regret
even a minute or a second of it
Never! (Never)
Create hope for whatever the future may bring
Don't wanna give up
Here I go, Look at me!
(Look at me!)
Everything is all right?
(Everything is all right?)
Don't be embarrassed, let yourself go
Kiss me now, on the right cheek
Dancing in the Moonlight
Listen to the music
(ah ah ha ha)
Dance throughout the galaxy
We'll always be together
Get ready (Are you ready?)
Dancing in the Moonlight
This light in the night
(Ah ah ha ha)
Shine endlessly
Our song will echo
endlessly, forever
We're meeting beneath the moon again today
But I'm still getting ready...!
"Wanna meet!"
"Wanna meet now!"
Gotta keep this impatience under control
"Music is Mystery",
"Music is Energy"
musi-C is Life"
"musi-C is Love"
"Music is Hope"
Okay, are we good?
Anyway,
Everybody let's go!
Farewell to sleepless nights
(Hold me tight,
hold me tight)
Can we meet again in a dream?
In my dream
(I just fall in love)
Take me now,
to the end of the galaxy
Don't stop, don't stop
(Don't stop)
I want all these passionate feelings to reach you
Oh my darling,
you're so cuuute
Call my name again
(Call my name)
Do you love me, Baby?
(Do you love me, Baby?)
If we ride this rhythm
and catch that star
Things will be even more wonderful
Wo, Wo, Wonderful
Dancing in the Moonlight
Feel the moonlight...
This rhythm can't be stopped!!
Dancing in the Moonlight
Listen to the music
(ah ah ha ha)
Dance throughout the galaxy
We'll always be together
Get ready
(Are you ready?)
Dancing in the Moonlight
This light, in the night
(ah ah ha ha)
Shine endlessly
Our song will echo endlessly, forever
Always, yeah
Lah Ia Ia Ia hah-
Wow wow wow wow
Dancing in the Moonlight